FABIO BORJA

DETAILS

ADDRESS

CDMX Mexico

PHONE

+52 5571179235

EMAIL

fabio.borja.portela@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

July 1999

EDUCATION & EXPERIENCE

- Mechanical Engineer, Faculty of Engineering UNAM
- Data Analyst Certification, Google & Inroads
- Project Management
 Certification, Google & Inroads
- Six Sigma White Belt Plus

SKILLS

SQL

PYTHON

POWER BI

LOOKER STUDIO

AWS

EMPLIFI

BRANDWATCH

MELTWATER

R STUDIO

PROFILE

I am an empathetic person with a sense of collective work that sees the common good as my own, proactive, organized, and responsible, with 5 years of experience working in professional fields related to Business Intelligence and Management Solutions.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Engineer, Meet Rise

Sep 2023 — Present

- Assistance through all data pipe levels oriented in fast response, triage, and client-oriented solutions.
- Deep understanding of SQL queries to manage data alterations in general, creation of Tables, Schemes, and Stored Procedures.
- Execution of Python/PySpark code oriented in ETL process, from source extraction and API connections, to transform and load data into servers.
- Experience with automation process in AWS Azkaban for data jobs execution and Apache Airflow.
- Knowledge of reading and understanding EMR files, the performance of clusters, instance selection, and progress logs.
- Gestion of AWS tools for S3 buckets for permanent files allocation, and Amazon Secrets for Access tokens.
- Fully understand covering SEO, Search, Social, Marketplaces & Programmatic, for different engines, such as Meta, Google Ads, Microsoft ads, TTD, etc.

Social Analyst, Teran TBWA

Mar 2023 — Sep 2023

- Help to Strategy Team with pitch phases oriented to create new marketing campaigns, product placement, or product promotion.
- ETL process by a full roadmap using tools provided by the developers of LinkedIn, Youtube, Meta, Twitter (X), Google Analytics, Shopify, and SuperMetrics.
- Use Python, SQL, and visualizers such as Power BI, Tableau, and Looker Studio to gather, extract, process, and present high-level reports to the client.

Data Analyst, Media Monks MX Aug 2022 — March 2023

Data Analyst Jr, Teran TBWA Nov 2020 — March 2022